Guide to Records Concerning Real Property and Legal Transactions near Cripple Creek, Colorado
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Maps, 1892-1935; Series V; 0.08; (1 box) + 17 rolls and 4 broadside folders
  - Davis, Lee W., and Byler, Emmett A.
    - Davis and Byler, Approved Mineral Surveys in the Cripple Creek Mining District: Teller County (Formerly Fremont and El Paso Counties), Colorado, Colorado Springs, Colorado: Edward R. March, 1900 January; 1 map, 121 x 91 cm. (Box 210 Broadside)
      Includes an alphabetical listing of mines indexed by section on map.
      Created for William P. Bonbright & Co., Bankers and Brokers, Colorado Springs, Colorado.
    - Davis and Byler, Approved Mineral Surveys in the Cripple Creek Mining District: Teller County (Formerly Fremont and El Paso Counties), Colorado, Victor, Colorado, 1901; 2 maps, 238 x 174 cm. (Box 211 Roll)
      Includes plats for the towns of Allman, Arequa, Cameron, Cripple Creek, Gillett, Goldfield, Independence, Lawrence, and Victor.
      Scale: 1 inch to 500 feet.
      - Duplicate Map, 1901 (Box 212 Roll)
  - Eddie, E. C., Eddie's New Claim Map of the Cripple Creek Mining District by E. C. Eddie, Denver, Colorado: E. C. Eddie, 1896; 1 map, 134 x 101 cm. (Box 213 Roll)
  - Funk, Walter A., Map of a Portion of Gilpin County: Showing Mining Claims in the Vicinity of Central City, Colorado, circa 1910; 1 map, 208 x 174 cm. (Box 214 Roll)
    Scale: 1 inch to 500 feet
  - Garston, William, and Hildreth Frost, Map of the Cripple Creek Mining District, Teller County, Colorado: Showing All Approved Mineral Surveys, Towns, Railroads, and Other Data, 1915; 1 map, 194 x 220 cm. (Box 215 Roll)
    Scale: 1 inch to 300 feet.
  - Lallie, J. S. J., Lallie's Correct Map of Cripple Creek Mining District, El Paso Co., Colorado, 1892 February 1; 1 map 105.6 x 89.2 cm. (Box 216 Broadside)
    Scale: 1 inch to 4000 feet.
    John St. J. Lallie (born 1864) was an attorney and proprietor of the Western Mathematical Instrument Works and the Lallie Instrument Co. in Denver, Colorado.
  - Nelson, Harry C., Detail Map of the Pinto Mine, Bison No. 2 Mine and Wilson Mine, 1935 April 8; 1 map, 45.8 x 61.6 cm. (Box 217 Roll)
  - Portland Gold Mining Company, Map of the Property of the Portland Gold Mining Company: Showing Surface Improvements and Topography of Battle Mountain, Cripple Creek Mining District, Colorado, circa 1900-1910; 1 map, 125.8 x 87.2 cm. (Box 218 Roll)
    Scale: 1 inch to 100 feet.
  - Reid, Herbert I., Myron Stratton Home Grounds, Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1931 February; 1 map 142.7 x 215.0 cm. (Box 219 Roll)
    Winfield Scott Stratton (1848-1902) left the bulk of his estate for the establishment of the Myron Stratton Home, for "the aged poor and dependent children" in Colorado Springs, Colorado, which he named for his father. After a series of lengthy probate challenges, the home was established in 1913.
    Includes locations of the administration building, dairy barn, dining room, greenhouse, halls, infirmary, powerhouse, storage buildings, superintendent building, and swimming pool.
    Scale: 1 inch to 30 feet.
    Engraved by Sanford and Phillips.
    Revised June 1, 1938 and April 1, 1939.
  - Snell, Edward, Map of Mining Claims on Cripple Creek, Pueblo, Colorado: Pueblo Lithography & Printing Co. for William A. Otis and Co., Bankers and Brokers Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1896 May; 2 maps, 88.8 x 63.7 cm. (Box 220 Broadside)
  - Torrington, T. R., The Mining Investigator's Claim Map of the Cripple Creek District, 1911 January 1; 2 maps, 124.2 x 81.0 cm. (Box 221 Roll)
    Scale 1 inch to 1000 feet
    - Duplicate map., 1911 January 1 (Box 222 Roll)
  - Zulch, Herman Charles. Prospector's Map, South Area, Cripple Creek District, Victor, Colorado, circa 1910; 1 map, 220.5 x 118.8 cm. (Box 223 Roll)